（忆往昔）
Dean 我现在真的很需要你
Dean, I could really use your help down here.
我就要抓到Abaddon了 Sam
I'm getting close, Sam.
我现在不能放弃这条路
I can't drop the ball on Abaddon right now.
我可以把该隐之印给你 如果这是你想要的
I can give you the mark Dean if it's what you truly want.
但你要知道 随之而来的负担非常沉重
But you have to know with the mark comes a great burden.
你到底想从我这儿得到什么 Metatron
What is it you want of me Metatron.
重建天堂
Rebuild Heaven.
你想做我的副手
You wanna be my second-in-command.
先证明你已经准备好了
Prove you're ready.
Gadreel 我们在撰写自己的史诗故事
Gadreel, we are writting our own epic story.
我拿回了我的荣光
Have my grace back.
确切来讲 不是我的 但是效果差不多
Not mine, per se, but, it'll do.
天使的内部争斗该结束了
Angels fighting angels has to stop somewhere.
你向我证明了 还有另一个选择
You showed me that there is a choice.
我不是领导者
I'm no leader.
我会追随你 而我不会是唯一一个
I will follow you and I'm not the only one.
（如今）
（邪恶力量 作者Carver Edlund 超自然圣诞节）
是什么让一个故事留存于世
What makes a story work.
是剧情吗
Is it the plot.
是角色 是遣词造句
The characters, the text.
或是潜台词
The subtext.
又是谁赋予了故事重大意义 是作者吗
And who gives the story meaning, is it the writer.
还是你
Or you.
今晚我给你讲一个小故事
Tonight I thought I would tell you a little story.
然后让你自己抉择
And let you decide.
嗯 好
Yeah, all right.
谢了 Carlos
Thanks, Carlos.Listen, you.
一旦发现任何恶魔活动的线索
If you catch wind bit more demon activity.
立刻打给我好吗
Give me a holler, all right.
非常感谢
Appreciate it.
嘿
Hey.
有进展吗
Anything.
有的
Yeah.
好几起恶魔相关案件
Dozen demon related cases.
被剥夺了灵魂的人活动频繁
People without souls acting out.
- 但是 - 没有Abaddon的消息
- But - But no sign of Abaddon.
没错 她就像是消失了一样
Right, like she's vanished.
那我们就必须继续调查
Well, we just have to keep digging.
好吧
All right.
你没事儿吧
You okay.
没事儿 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
- 继续工作 - 好
- Let's get to work - All right.
求你 求你别伤害我
Please, please don't, don't hurt me.
我不会伤害你的
I'm not gonna hurt you.
没事儿的
It's okay.
你叫什么名字
What's your name.
Hannah
Hannah.
Hannah 这里发生了什么
Hannah, what happened here.
我听到你的声音了 到底是怎么回事
I heard your tune.What was it.
我不知道
I don't know.
那声音很耳熟
It sounded familiar.
听起来就像是天堂
Sounded like heaven.
这里一切都很奇怪
It's so strange down here.
我循着那声音来到这里
I followed the tone.
发现了很多兄弟姐妹
And found so many of my brothers and sisters as well.
我以为会是安全的
I felt safe here.
可突然门就关上了
And then the door slammed shut.
然后那个奇怪的天使出现了
And a strange angel arrived.
他说他听命于新的上帝
He said he worked for the new god.
听命于Metatron吗
For Metatron.
他给我们提出了条件
He made us an offer.
效忠Metatron
Join Metatron.
为他而战
Fight for him.
归顺的天使
And those that did would one day be.
就可以回归天堂
Allowed to return to heaven.
怎么回归天堂
Return to heaven.
我也没信
I didn't believe him either.
但他说他能带我们回家
But he said he would take us home.
一些天使动摇了
Some angels joined him.
我和我的朋友们拒绝了
My friends and I refused.
然后
And.
我为你感到难过
I'm sorry for your loss.
为我们所有人感到难过
For all our loss.
你是Castiel
You're Castiel.
是吗
Aren't you.
是的
Yes.
你公开和Bartholomew作对
You took stand against Bartholomew.
你会帮我们吗
Are you going to help us.
会领导我们一起对付Metatron吗
Lead us against Metatron.
我不是领导者
I'm no leader.
- 但是 - 我不是当领袖的人 Hannah
- But - I am no leader, Hannah.
但是我会找到Metatron的
But I will find Metatron.
让他付出代价
And I will make him pay.
让我帮你
Let me help you.
让我们帮你
Let us help you.
你离我越远 就越安全
You are safer away from me.
好了 那个攻击你的天使
Now, this angel who attacked you.
他叫什么
What was his name.
Gadreel吗 Gadreel成了Metatron的手下
Gadreel?Gadreel is working for Metatron.
什么时候的事
How long.
我不知道
I don't know.
所以说Metatron让Gadreel杀了Kevin
So, Metatron made Gadreel kill Kevin.
这样就说得通了
Well, it would explain a lot.
而且从那之后就没有先知了
And, there have been no new prophets.
Metatron能充分利用自己的长处
Which Metatron could've fixed to his advantage.
Gadreel说
And Gadreel said.
那些天使要怎么回天堂去
That the angels returning the heavan how.
我以为那个咒语是不可逆转的
I thought the spell was irreversible.
那是Crowley那么说的
That's what Crowley said.
听着我们去找Gadreel
Look, let's just find Gadreel and.
严刑拷问他
Beat some answers out of him.
我这儿有线索
Here's something to start with that.
等一下 我正在
Hold on, I'm.
给你发一张照片
Sending you a photo of the symbol.
上面的符号召集了很多天使
That drew all the angels in.
好的
OK.
收到了
Got it.
这东西像是一个天使报警器
It's acting as…some kind of angel siren.
我觉得应该是个符咒
I think that's a spell.
用来激活咒语的材料很罕见
The ingredients used to creat it were very odd.
狮鹫的羽毛 精灵的骨头
Griffin feathers, bonds of a fairy.
我从来没见过这个
And I've never seen it before.
我也没有
Yeah, me neither.
好吧 我们找找看
All right, let me see what we can find.
（荣誉栏）
汽车旅馆里的军用酒吧
What's honorable about a miniature bar.
哪里光荣了
In the motel room.
哪里都光荣
Everything.
你还好吗Dean
How are you Dean.
我挺好的 你呢
I'm fine Cass, how about you.
我想念我的翅膀
I miss my wings.
四处奔波
Life on the road.
臭不可闻
Smells.
是啊
Yeah.
我找到了
Listen, I got match.
不是任何神话传说
And it's not from the lore.
而是警方记录
It's from police records.
这个符咒这几天
Looks like that symbol you found was spotted.
频繁出现在凶杀案现场
At a handful of crime scenes the last couple of days.
都是多重凶杀
All multiple homicides.
犯罪现场都在什么地方
And where were these crime scenes.
犹他州的 贝克镇 谷峰镇
Utah, Baker, Hill Valley.
我就在犹他州的西隆镇
And I'm in Bishop's Falls, Utah.
而且好像大部分犯罪现场
Also looks like most crime scenes.
都在工业区
Were in industrial areas.
看来Gadreel在往北走
Looks like Gadreel was heading north.
下一个大镇是什么
What's next big town.
有两个
There are two.
可能是奥本 或者奥格登
Could be Auburn or Ogden.
你去奥本 我们去奥格登
All right you take the Auburn we take Ogden.
到时候见
Meet in the middle.
我们是不是在奥格登办过案子
Did we work a case in Ogden.
是的
Yeah.
好像是个女巫事件
It…it was a witch situation, right.
是啊
Yeah.
镇上有个小伙帮过我们对吧
And there was a kid in town that helped us, wasn't there.
对 我们应该给他打电话 看他是不是还在
Yes, we should call him, see if he's still in business.
好 他叫什么来着
Yeah, what was his name.
下午好
Good afternoon.
已经是下午了吗
It's afternoon.
我能不能在你这儿买点东西
I wonder if I may procure from you.
狮鹫的羽毛
The feathers of griffin.
我们是有些私下出售的物品
Uh…we got some off the menu items.
但是这儿不是对角巷
But this ain't Diagon Alley, man.
我看到门上的标识了 伙计
I saw the Hunter signs on the door, young man.
你这儿有我想要的
You have what I seek.
狮鹫的羽毛是吧
Griffin feathers, huh.
不是想拿着去酒吧泡妞吧
Not exactly looking to trip the light fantastic, are we.
人类总是惊喜不断
Humans never cease to amaze me.
你说什么
Excuse me.
我是问
I'm curious.
是不是还有精灵的骨头
Do you also have fairy bones.
出生的地域并不重要
Does not matter what realm they were from.
狮鹫和精灵 你到底是想抓什么啊
Griffins and faries, the hell you're hunting, man.
家人
Family.
好吧
Okay.
我看看能找到什么
Let me see what we have here.
有的时候你需要从
Sometime you need a break.
急匆匆的城市生活中喘一口气
From hustle and bustle of city life.
我说的对吗
Hash tag Am I Right.
有的时候你只是需要
Sometime you need.
色情古堡
Hash tag CasaErotica.
Casa Erotica.
太不正经了
That's inappropriate.
你好
Hello.
小子 记得我吗
Remember me, bucko.
Gabriel
Gabriel.
我就当你记得了
I'm gonna take that as a yes.
我需要你的帮助 弟弟
I need your help, brother.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
拜托
Please.
半仙不耍戏法还叫半仙吗
You can't take the trick out of the trickster.
我猜你一手制造了你的假死
So I assume you faked your own death.
我猜 我不在的时候
And I assume you weren't letting to Mensa.
你把上面搅乱了
When I was gone.
你去哪了
Where have you been.
噢 你懂我的
Oh…you know.
这儿跑跑 那儿转转
Hither with a side of yon.
我一直躲着 冷面队长
I was hiding, captain side eyes.
躲在世界上最安全的地方
In the safest place in the universe.
天堂
Heavan.
但是没过多久
But then you.
你和那两个傻帽就非得要
And the other two stooges just had to go.
搅得天下大乱 对吗
And ruin Christmas now, didn't ya.
对不起
Sorry.
呵呵呵
Oh cry me a river.
听着 我退出了 我隐居了
Look, I dropped, I hid.
我终于看了唐顿庄园
I finally watched Downton Abbey.
然后你的好闺蜜Metatron
But then, your BFF Metatron.
派出他的狗腿手下成天找我
Sent his minions out looking for me.
显然 他觉得既然我是一个大天使
Apparently he thinks since I'm an Archangel.
那我肯定还没死透
That I have extra juice.
- 所以你是个威胁 - 没错
- That you're a threat - Yeah.
但我也在堕天时受了伤
But I got hurt in the fall, too.
挤进那个色情片几乎耗尽了我所有荣光
Used most of my juice to get back in a porn.
我是不是说漏嘴了
That…came out wrong.
这一句也是
So do that.
总之重点是
Uh the point is.
我一直在逃路
I've been on the run.
但是 几周之前
But then, a few weeks ago.
我被召唤了
Somebody started playing my song.
警报
The angel siren.
不
No.
加百列之角
The Horn of Gabriel.
老爹手里的小宝贝之一
One of dad's little party favours.
我一直都没怎么玩儿过呢
That I have never got around to messing with.
Metatron发现了它
Metatron dug it up.
然后吹响了号角
And started blowing.
于是
So.
我决定重新现身
I came out of hiding.
为什么
Why.
虽然天使们人多势众
They're safety in numbers.
但是Metatron用号角抓捕天使
But Metatron's using it to trap angels.
而不是集结他们
Not unite them.
那不是Metatron干的
It wasn't Metatron.
是他的副手Gadreel
It was his second-in-command, Gadreel.
Gadreel
Gadreel.
那个老不死的
That old chestnut.
你想让我做什么
What do you want from me.
我需要你的帮助 机灵鬼
Your help, Columbo.
我要建立新的力量
I'm getting the band back together.
然后追着Metatron猛打
We're going on the kill Metatron tour.
站在你面前的是一线队员
And you're looking at the new front man.
Sam
Sam.
这儿有一盒子羽毛
Got an open box of feathers over here.
Dean
Dean.
我们得在Gadreel发出指令前
We got to find Gadreel.
找到他
Before he lights up the bad signal.
这是Dean另外 另外一个号码
It's Dean's other, other cell.
所以你知道该怎么做
So must know what to do.
Dean 是我
Dean, it's me.
开着车呢
Hands free much.
把爪子放方向盘上 我可是贵重货物
Put those on the wheel, I'm precious cargo.
嘿 最近怎么样啊 小矮子们
Hey, what's up, shorties.
还记得我吗
Remember me.
为了你们的罪孽英勇牺牲
The guy who died for your sins.
不
No.
不是满脸胡子穿着凉鞋的大叔
Not the guy with the beard in the sandals.
是更帅的那个
The hot one.
对了
Hey.
非常感谢你们给我送花还替我哀悼
Thank you so much for the flowers and condolences.
对我的家人是很大的慰藉
Really meant a lot to the fam.
不管怎样
Any old how.
我正跟你们的小男宠在一起
Your boy toy and I.
我们正在去秘密基地的路上
Are rolling our way towards our top secret domicile.
打给我
Call to discuss.
那两个小毛孩
Those gooky kids.
所以你已经回来好几个月了是吗
So you've been back for months.
你都看见了什么
What have you seen out there.
先是满天掉长翅膀的怪人
After it was raining winged men.
哈利路亚
Hallelujah.
在天堂混乱局面后
You know.Total nigh biblical chaos.
Crolwey
Crowley.
Abaddon小蠢蛋
And Aba-duch.
打得不可开交
Duking it out.
还挺有看点
Good times.
然后是我们的人
Then there's our buds.
像纸屑一样分崩离析
Scattered like confetti.
有一阵子所有人都很不适应
It has been a lot of confusion.
还用你说
You think.
大多数天使跟我们不一样 Castiel
Most angels aren't like us, Castiel.
他们没法接受自由意志这种东西
They can't handle this whole…free will thing.
他们就像羊群
They are sheep.
不知所措
Drones.
但是我们
But us.
我们不一样
We're different.
我们是反叛者
We're rebels.
一个初出茅庐 一个已经有了一番事业
One without a cause, one with.
我只是个士兵
I'm just a soldier.
别矫情了 贱人
Bitch, please.
你做上帝的时间比老爹都长
You've been God often than dad has.
那结果又如何呢
Look how that worked out.
好吧 随你
Well, go ahead.
当你的好士兵去吧
Be a soldier all you want.
我需要的士兵可是越多越好
I'm gonna need as many as I can find.
你为什么要这么做 Gabriel
Why are you doing this Gabriel.
我一直都在逃
I always run.
逃离老爹 逃离家庭
From dad, from the family.
我不想再逃了
I don't want to run anymore.
我要干我应该做的事情
I wanna do what I was meant to do.
领导
Lead.
我们需要一个领导者
We need a leader.
如果是你 我会很高兴的
I'm happy it's gonna be you.
好像需要加点儿油了 是不是
A little low on gas, aren't we.
闻到致癌物质的气息了吗
Smell that cancer.
真是美味啊
Delicious.
还记得我跟你提过的Metatron护卫队吗
Remember the minions of Metatron I mentioned.
Cas 还是我 Sam
Cas, it's Sam again.
回个电话 我们需要你
Call us, we need your help.
看这 狗东西
Hey, douche bag.
还记得我吗
Remember me.
我们不可能阻止他们进来
We'd never keep these guys out there.
我知道 那又怎样 我们可以并肩作战
I know.So?We fight.
不 只有我一个人
No, I fight.
我之前是骗你的 我从来没有看过唐顿庄园
I lied before, I never watched Downtown Abbey.
我只是想融入社会而已
I was just trying to fit in.
对了 我还剩下一些圣油
Oh, and I do have some archangel juice left.
我可以抵挡这帮蠢家伙足够长的时间
And I can hold these boneheads off long enough.
然后呢
Long enough for what.
足够你离开这里
For you to get out of here.
不 我不会离开你
No, I'm not leaving you.
你必须走
Yes, you are.
这些家伙会把你砍成碎片的
Those guys will cut you to ribbons.
但是我可以他们拖住
But I can stall them long enough for you to amscray.
你可以接替我的位置
You can take my place.
你在说什么
What are you talking about.
天使们需要一个领袖
The angels need a leader.
像我们这样的
It got to be somebody like us.
与众不同的领袖
Somebody different.
不
No.
我知道你要要这个包袱Castiel
I know you don't want this burden, Castiel.
我也不想
Neither do I.
要是我又失败了怎么办
What if I fail again.
你不会的
You won't.
你输不起
You can't.
谢谢你
Thank you.
闭嘴
Shut up.
时间很紧哦 帅哥
Haven't got all day, hot pants.
这一切是真的吗
Was any of these real.
你说什么
What the hell are you talking about.
快走啊 Cass
Cass, go.
不然我们都得死在这里
So what, we both die here.
不 你已经死了
No, you already dead.
好吧
Well.
是哪里露馅了
What gave it all away.
我的风衣之前撕坏了
My coat was torn earlier today.
该死
Oh, crap.
我最烦这种一出错就全露馅
I really hate continuity errors.
所以 这些都不是真的
So, none of these is real.
我想我现在也不在旅馆里了
And I'm guessing I'm no longer in the motel.
事情是这样
Here's the thing.
虽然这些不是真实的 但是却是真理
None of it was real, but all of it was true.
谁的真理
Whose truth.
你的 还是Metatron的
Yours, or Metatron's.
听我说完 好吗
Just hear now, would you.
他想要帮助你
He is trying to help you.
是吗 怎么帮
Really?How.
抱歉
Sorry.
他的手稿我没全看完
Didn't read the whole scripts.
只看了有我的部分
Just skimmed for my parts.
总之 很高兴见到你 老兄
Well, it's good to see you, old bean.
等等
Wait.
你真的死了吗
Are you dead.
什么样的故事才能留存于世
What makes a story work.
如果我觉得我是在看哈哈镜
If this is like looking a fun house mirror for me.
我简直没法想象你是怎么看的了
I can not imagine how is it like for you.
你从什么时候开始为Metatron卖命
How long have you been working for Metatron.
我不会开口的 你逼我也没有用
I will not talk, and you can not make me.
是吗
Yeah.
我曾经附在你身上 Sam Winchester
I've been you, Sam Winchester.
你内心是如此愧疚和脆弱
You are inside reek of shame and weakness.
Sam Sam Sam
Sam, Sam, Sam.
到这来 门外说话
Come here, door.
今晚 我给你讲个故事
Tonight I thought I'd tell you a little story.
让你来做决定
Let you decide.
这是我原本的计划
That was my plan anyway.
我猜 这就是我计划的疏漏之处
I guess that's where my story failed.
没错
Yes.
就是这个有趣的小插曲
This is the curious incident.
对不对啊 Granderye侦探
Eh, Inspector Granderye.
谁
Who.
Gregory探长
Inspector Gregory.
Sherlock Holmes知道吗
Sherlock Holmes.
看白额闪电（出自《福尔摩斯探案集》）吗
Silver Blaze.
你从人类
You have been here around.
进化成功的第一天就来了
Since scaly things crawled out of the muck.
去读读书 看看电影你会死吗
Would it kill you to pick up a book, watch a movie.
可能会比较痛苦
Here, I know it's a bit of a redcon, but it's.
不过 这会让我们之间的谈话变得简单的多
Gonna make this whole conversation a lot easier.
我刚刚把最近几个世纪我看过的
I just gave you every book, movie and TV show.
所有书籍 电影和电视节目都共享给你了
I have consumed in the last couple of millennia.
现在你是否明白
Now, do you understand that.
世界是由故事构成
The universe is made up of the stories.
而不是原子
Not atoms.
我知道
I understand that's.
这句话出自Muriel Rukeyser的作品
A quote by Muriel Rukeyser.
朽木可雕啊
You can be taught.
还有几节课要上
Here're a few more lessones.
写作俱乐部的第一原则
First rule of the writers' club.
天下文章一大抄
Steal from the best.
第二条原则 每个英雄都需要一个大反派
Second rule, every hero needs a villian.
你是什么意思
What are you talking about.
Hannah 还有她的姐妹
Hannah, and her sisters.
都是我捏造出来的
I set all that up.
我告诉Gadreel
Told Gadreel.
杀光所有不愿意听命于我的人
Slaughter all those who are not join to my army.
除了一个
But let one live.
只有一个
One.
让他来讲述这个故事
To tell the tale.
这是真的吗
Is it true.
你能把天使们送回天堂吗
Can you bring angel back to heaven.
抱歉 不能剧透
Sorry, no spoilers.
你总是搞错重点
And you keep missing the point.
你应该领导这些天使
You are supposed to lead the angels.
我不是领袖 Metatron
I am not a leader, Metatron.
我知道
Apparently.
所以 我做了做功课
So, I did my homework.
Winchester福音书
The Winchester Gospels.
还是纸质的
Pulpy stuff.
但是给我了启发
Give me an idea though.
你需要上一课
You need to be taught a lesson.
没有人比Gabriel这老家伙
And nobody teaches lessones.
更适合了给人上课
Better than good old Gabrial.
也就是半仙
AKA the trickster.
所以 我开始打字
So, I started typing.
你做了这一切
You did all this.
就为了让我成为英雄吗
To make me a hero.
真有意思
That's priceless.
不
No.
你不是这部作品里的英雄
You are not the hero in this mess-terpiece.
你是反派
You are the villian.
我才是英雄
I'm the hero.
他不会这么快就交代的
He's not gonna crack that fast.
我知道
I know.
不然你入侵他的思想
Maybe you could hack him.
就像当初你和Crowley对我那样
Like you and Crowley hacked me.
不行
No, no.
这只有Crowley才能办到
Crowley is the only one can do that.
我这会儿没心情给那老不死的打电话
And I'm in no mood to call that dickbag.
我们需要Cass
We need Cass.
有消息吗
Any word from him.
没有 我试着找过他
No.I tried him again.
他不接电话也不回短信
He hasn't called, he hasn't texted.
我开了他手机上的GPS
I turned on the GPS on his phone.
他还在我们上次和他谈话的那个镇上
He's still in the same town we talked to him last.
怎么会
What the hell.
我不知道 你必须去找到他
I don't know, you gotta go find him.
什么
What.
你对这件事太感情用事了
You're too close to this, man.
你就不是吗
And what, you are not.
我们抓到他还没5分钟
We're not at this five minutes.
你差点儿就把他卸了
You're going Liam Neeson on his ass.
我搞定这里
I got this.
所以是他唱红脸 你唱白脸
So, he acts tough and you show kindness.
是这样对吧
Is that how this works.
不
No.
要知道 我根本不在乎你是否会开口
See, I don't care whether you talk.
你都会为你对他所做的事情付出代价
You gotta pay for what you did to him.
还有Kevin的死
And Kevin.
你知道为什么我没有杀你吗
Do you know why I didn't kill you.
在我偷了你的荣光之后
After I stole you grace.
我喜欢你 真的
I like you, truly.
上帝的那些小玩具里
Among all God's little windup toys.
就你还有几分勇气
You were the only one with any spunk.
我将你变成人类
I left you human.
是希望你能在人间从此过上幸福的生活
Because I was hoping you would live happily ever after.
结果你连那个也搞砸了
You screwed that up, too.
如今
And, now.
你让我别无选择
You leave me no choice.
我是说如果你想要重新加入
I mean if you wanna get back on board.
没问题 但是你必须跟着我的剧本走
Fine, but you‘re gonna have to follow my script.
根据你之前的评价
Based on your assessment.
这不是我会做的选择
That doesn't sound like me.
领导那些愚蠢的
Lead the dumb.
被剥夺权利的天使反抗我 Castiel
Disenfranchised rebellious angel against me, Castiel.
假如他们选择跟随你
They would follow you.
最后就只有死路一条
And they will all die.
但是我会在上面给你留一个好位置的
But I'm gonna save a nice warm seat up top for you.
- 你会被拯救的 - 想都别想
- You will be saved - No.
你一定要逼我下狠手 是不是
You gonna make me do the hard pitch, aren't you.
你体内偷来的荣光现在如何了
How's that stolen grace inside you working out.
很好
It's fine.
不 显然不好
No, it's not.
它在燃烧 会把你化成灰烬
It's burnning out, it's gonna burn you out.
但是我可以给你无尽的资源
But I will give you an endless supply.
一块可以反复充电的电池
Of rechargeable battery.
同意吗
Deal.
长官 抱歉打扰您的写作
Sorry to interrupt your writing session, sir.
但是有事情发生了
But something's happened.
什么事
What's wrong.
是Gadreel
It's Gadreel.
坊间流传
Words around the campfire is.
是你把蛇放进了伊甸园
You let the snake into the garden.
是你让人类堕落
Ruined it for all the humanity.
是我给了他们自由
I set them free.
我深爱人类
I loved humanity.
好吧 你表达爱的方式可有点可笑 蠢货
Well, you sure got a funny way of showing it, asshat.
现在这样
Now look.
告诉我
You tell me.
你们回到天堂的所有计划
About this getting back into the heaven crap.
我给你一个痛快的
And I will end this quick.
否则
Otherwise.
你就坐在这跟这些铁链一起腐烂
You can sit there rot in those chains forever.
自己选吧
Up to you.
所有你说的话 装腔作势
All your talk, all your bluster.
你以为你是无可匹敌的
You think you are unvincible.
你们两人 对抗世界 对吧
The two of you against the world, right.
没错 你说对了
Damn, straight.
你真的以为Sam会为了你做任何事
You really think Sam will do anything for you.
我知道他会的
Oh I know he would.
我曾经在你弟弟的身体里 Dean
I've been in your brother's body, Dean.
他不会拿他的命来换回你的
He would not trade his life for yours.
多谢提醒啊 兄弟
Well, thanks for the rerun, pal.
Sam已经跟我说过这些了
Sam's already told me all that crap.
不 他说的还要更糟糕
No, he has told me worse.
他告诉你他一直是这样想的了吗
He told you that he has always felt that way.
他有没有说
That he thinks.
他觉得你只是个胆小怕事的小男孩
You are just a scared little boy.
害怕自己一个人被留下
Who is afraid to be on his own.
因为你从来得不到父亲足够的爱护
Because daddy never loves him enough.
他是对的
And he is right, isn't he.
你就是个懦夫
Right to think you are a coward.
一个软弱无能的 索求无度
A sad, clingy, needy.
继续说
Keep it up.
可悲的 卑微的底层生物
Pathetic, bottom feeder.
连自己都照顾不了
Who can not even take care of himself.
宁愿拉上所有人
Who would rather drag everyone.
也不愿自己一个
Through the mud than be alone.
所有他身边的人都得替他死
Who would let everyone around him die.
来啊 下手啊
No, do it.
下手啊
Do it.
杀了我
Kill me.
你要的就是这个效果 对吧
Oh, you'd like that, wouldn't you.
所以你才故意激怒我的
That's what all that speech was about.
你不怕死 对吗
You're not afraid to die, are you.
你怕的是我把你一直锁在这儿
You're afraid to be left on these chains forever.
你就在这儿等死吧
You could sit here and rot.
狗娘养的混蛋
You son of a bitch.
（来自Dean的6个未接来电）
放轻松 小老虎
Easy there, tiger.
我是来做交易的
I'm here to trade.
你手里有我的东西
You have something of mine.
我手里有你的东西
And I have something of yours.
明天早上带他来
Bring him here tomorrow.
6点左右吧
Say…six-ish.
如果不来 Castiel就会死
If not, Castiel dies.
这次他可没法复活了
No come-backs this time.
你不会临时变卦吧
An even trade.
我一向说话算话
I'm an entity of my word.
（Sam来电）
Dean
Dean.
Dean!Hey.
你还好吗
Are you okay.
还好 下次换个问题问
Yeah, you got to stop asking me that.
我一直在给你打电话
I've been calling you.
- 你怎么不 - 他什么都不肯说
- Why don't you - He won't talk.
我后来发现
I figured.
他想死
He wanted to die.
我本来打算杀了他
And I was gonna kill him.I was.
但是我没有 因为我知道他活着还有用
But then I stopped 'cause I know we need him to talk.
Dean 听着
Dean, listen.
Metatron抓走了Cass
Metatron has Cass.
他想跟我们交换
He's offering us a trade.
我们什么时候能相信Metatron了
We can't trust Metatron.
我知道
I know that.Obviously.
但是 这是我们第一次有机会
Look, this is the first time we're gonna know.
知道Metatron到底是何方神圣
For sure what Metatron is.
我们就把Gadreel带去
Let's take Gadreel to the meet-up.
做了交换之后 困住Metatron
Make the exchange, and then trap Metatron.
他迟到了
He's late.
或者根本不打算来
Or he's not gonna show.
我当然会来了
Of course I'm gonna show.
我只是在等你们两个
I was just waiting for you two to.
把你们的陷阱弄好
Finished setting up your little trap for me.
我站的地方对吗
Am I hitting my mark.
来吧 赶紧的
Well, come on, let's go.
还愣着干什么
I'm waiting.
你们谁还有多余的料吗
Either of you brings s'mores.
圣火总是有一股
Holy fire always gives them a.
温愠的薄荷味儿
Delightful minty after taste.
许个愿吧
Make a wish, boys.
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
拜拜
Bye bye.
交易还是要做的
Well, a deal is a deal.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this.
因为我有这个能力
Because I can.
因为你 你弟弟
Because you, and your little brother.
你的天使朋友
And your fine feathered friend.
还有你藏在基地里的那些小秘密
And all the secrets you got locked away.
都没法阻止我
In your bunker can't stop me.
但我会享受看你们挣扎的过程
But I am gonna enjoy watching you try.
绝对会是一出好戏
It's gonna be hell of a show.
再见了 Castiel
I'll see you around, Castiel.
别忘了我给过你机会
Never forget I gave you a chance.
谁跟我说说
Somebody wanna tell me.
现在到底什么情况
What the hell is going on here.
Metatron想当上帝
Metatron is trying to play God.
想当上帝
Play God.
Cass 他轻松抹掉了天使驱逐符咒
Cass, he erased angel warding.
他 他还吹灭了圣火
He freaking…blew the holy fire.
他就是上帝
He is God.
他在用天使预言石的力量
He's powering up with the angel tablet.
我们怎么可能阻止得了他
How the hell are we supposed to stop this guy.
好吧 如果真的有办法回归天堂
All right, so what if there is a stairway to Heaven.
我们就去那儿守株待兔
We find it and get a drop on the guy.
你是想一路潜行到死星（《银河帝国》中的军事要塞）
You want to sneak onto the Death Star.
然后一举拿下人家帝王吗
And take out the emperor.
我不是很清楚
Okay, I'm not sure.
你们说的科幻太空要塞跟现在有什么关系
What a fictional battle station in space has to do with this.
但是如果拿下帝王
But if taking out the Emperor.
等于除去Metatron
Means taking out the Metatron.
- 我愿意加入 - 等等 你
- I'm on board - Wait, did you.
你刚听懂了我们说的梗吗
Did you just understand the Death Star reference.
我觉得是
Yeah, I think so.
但是我不明白
But I don't understand what.
那些跟天堂有什么关系
That has to do with heaven.
差不多吧 我猜
It's halfway I guess.
你确定你还好吗
You sure you're all right.
是的
Yes.
你呢
Are you.
你有一些不一样
There's something different about you.
我没事
I'm fine.
你干了什么
What have you done.
- 我想终结一切 - 该死的 Dean
- This means to an end - Damnit, Dean.
你找到天堂入口了 告诉我们一声
Look, you find heaven you drop a dime.
我还有个地狱骑士要处理
Meantime, I got a knight to kill.
你自己小心
Be safe out there.
你也是
You too.
Sam
Hey, Sam.
看着他点儿
You keep an eye on him.
那扇门安全了吗
Is the door secure.
是的
Yes.
回家的路很安全
The way home is safe.
谢谢你 Gadreel
Thank you, Gadreel.
你的剧写得怎么样了
How did your play turn out.
跟以前设想的 稍微有些出入
Didn't quite turn out as I planned.
所以我们才删稿重写
But that is why we re-write.
都是上帝惹的麻烦
That was God's problem, you know.
发了第一稿之后
You published the first draft.
你就得
You got to.
不停的修改 让你想要的故事进行下去
Keep editting to get all your ducks in a row.
Winchester兄弟抓住我
Was the Winchesteres grabbing me.
也在计划之内吗
Part of your plan.
那是个意外的惊喜
That was a surprise.
话说回来 哪个作家不喜欢剧情转折呢
But, hey, what a writer doesn't love a good twist.
我的工作
My job.
是建立好生动的人物形象
Is to set up interesting characters.
看他们会带给我怎样的故事
And see where they lead me.
随之而来的副产品 是这些丰满的人物形象
The by-product of having well-drawn characters is.
有时候会给你带来惊喜
They may surprise you.
但是我知道他们不知道的事
But I know something they don't know.
结局
The ending.
结局怎么走 不重要
How I get there, doesn't matter.
重要的是每个角色各司其职
As long as everybody plays their part.
（你注定是领导者）
（Castiel走出去加入了他的追随者）
（上帝在云端看着他们 对自己的作品表示满意）
（未完待续）